<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mitanshi Vyas on Mitanshi Vyas</title>
    <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mitanshi Vyas on Mitanshi Vyas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a graduate student at Northeastern University. My name is Mitanshi Vyas and I am currently working as a Research Assistant at Khoury College of Computer Sciences for Northeastern Civic A.I. Lab aimed towards studying and building public A.I. tech to empower Gig Workers.
I am currently working on a Work Culture Project aimed towards modeling the data from crowdsourcing platforms such as Toloka and Upwork. I am also working towards building a Recommender system and Spam Filtering Model for tasks being posted on such crowdsourcing platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Connect with me via these platforms:
Platform URL Website: https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/ LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mitanshivyas/ GitHub: https://github.com/mitanshivyas Slack: https://crowdactivism.slack.com/team/U041M9DPJ2X Instagram: https://instagram.com/mitanshivyas?igshid=YmMyMTA2M2Y= Email: vyas.mit@northeastern.edu Contact: +1(857)-264-8359 Location: Boston, MA </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: MCQ Generator and Text Similarity Model</title>
      <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The project aims to build an MCQ generation model utilizing a custom summarizer model and a BERT summarizer model The model includes key word extraction process in order to map the most relevant sentences from the summary to frame the questions and the answer choices are created using the trivial process of keeping the right answer(key word) as one of the options and adding distractors to fill up the choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Loan Delinquency Prediction</title>
      <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The aim of the project was to visualize the relationships between Loan Delinquency against other attributes in the dataset and build a Logistic Regression Model to predict the Loan Delinquency by a given customer. Tidied and transformed the dataset Utilized Matplotlib and Seaborn to plot visualizations between various variables Combined census data with the original data to plot spatial visualizations using ‘sf’ library Deployed three classification models with XGboost, Random Forest and Gaussian Naïve Bayes for Model Evaluation The Gaussian Naive Bayes model gave the best accuracy (89.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Microsoft Malware Prediction</title>
      <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Malware, short for malicious software, is an invasive software that is designed to infect, damage or gain unauthorized access to computer systems It is extremely important to build a system that is robust and does not easily get compromised by malware The project aims to predict the probability of a Windows machine of getting compromised by malware based on various properties of the machine Predicted whether themachine would soon be attacked or not by applying machine learning models using gradient boosting methods implemented using LightGBM The dataset was originally 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Hidden Markov Model</title>
      <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>From scratch implementation of Hidden Markov Model utilizing the Forward-Backward algorithm and Expectation-Maximization for probabilities optimization The HMM is one of the most commonly used algorithms in Natural Language Processing, and is a foundation to many deep learning techniques In addition to parts-of-speech tagging, HMM is used in speech recognition, speech synthesis, etc. Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Image Classification with Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>The project aims at building a classification model for the provided CIFAR-10 dataset which is an image dataset This is achieved by applying two classification approaches: Deep Learning with Convolution layer (CNN), and Artificial Neural Network (ANN) The CIFAR-10 Dataset is an important image classification dataset It consists of 60000 32x32 colour images in 10 classes (airplanes, automobiles, birds, cats, deer, dogs, frogs, horses, ships, and trucks), with 6000 images per class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 6: COVID-19 EDA</title>
      <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this project was to perform exploratory data analysis on COVID-19 dataset and gain insights from it Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post2/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitanshivyas.github.io/Mitanshi_Portfolio/post2/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Exploring 5G- Technologies, challenges, and 5G for enhancement of IoT
Pandey, S., Vyas, M., Mangal, A. Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, UIT-RGPV, Bhopal, India
5G is the fifth-generation wireless technology for digital cellular networks. The present-day cellular communication requires better quality of service, improved data rate, increased capacity, decreased latency, and improved communication network and security. Various technologies have evolved which will serve as a backbone in the establishment of 5G.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
